Guide to the African American Chamber of Commerce of Western Pennsylvania Digital Archive AACCWP
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Events, II.
  - Business Institute Workshops, 3.
    - How to do Business with Duquesne Light Company, May 11, 2018
    - Business Communications Workshop, July 26, 2018
    - How to do Business with Turner Construction Company, September 11, 2018
    - Manufacturing Supply Chain Workshop, November 13, 2018
    - Trends Workshop, November 23, 2018
    - Southwestern PA Demographic Challenge Workshop, January 10, 2019
    - How to do Business with Allegheny County Airport Authority, January 23, 2019
    - How to do Business with Port Authority, February 21, 2019
    - How to do Business with City of Pittsburgh, March 20, 2019
    - How to do Business with Rivers Casino, March 26, 2019
    - How to do Business with Huntington Bank, April 11, 2019
    - How to do Business with Pittsburgh Pirates, April 30, 2019
    - Fraud Workshop, May 15, 2019
    - Grow with Google Workshop, June 18, 2019
    - Cybersecurity Workshop, June 20, 2019
    - Meet the Primes, July 25, 2019
    - How to do Business with Parter4Work, 2019-09-10
    - How to do Business with CCAC, 2019-09-23
    - How to do Business with Equitrans Midstream, 2019-10-22
    - How to do Business with United States Steel Corp, 2020-02-21
    - Brain Health-Keys to Sucessful Aging, 2019-09-11
    - Grow with Google, 2019-12-09
    - Tax Exempt Financing, 2020-01-22
    - Caregivers call to Action, 2020-01-29
    - Elevator Pitch Webinar, 2020-07-30
    - Brain health-Resource Workshop for the Community, 2020-09-09
    - Economic Equality Webinar, 2020-09-28
    - Data Privacy and Compliance Webinar, 2020-09-29
  - Candidate Forums, 4.
    Each primary season, the Chamber holds a political forum to ask two basic questions: What have you done to support the growth of African American business owners and professionals. And, if elected what would you do to support the growth of African American business owners and professionals. Each session is moderated by the Managing Editor of the New Pittsburgh Courier. Members and guests are encouraged to write their questions on a panel card found at their seat. The staff of the Chamber collects the cards and gives them to the Moderator to read and tabled with the candidates. The responses are timed by Chamber staff to keep the dialogue moving and to include maximum participation from the audience.
    - Mayoral Candidates and Superior Court Judicial Candidates, March 21, 2001
    - Pittsburgh City Council District 9 Candidates, February 18, 2002
    - Gubernatorial Candidates and PA Senator Candidates and PA State Representative Candidates, April 10, 2002
    - Allegheny County Chief Executive Candidates, September 11, 2003
    - PA State Representative Candidates, April 1, 2004
    - Mayoral Candidates, April 21, 2005
    - Lieutenant Governor Candidates and PA State Representative Candidates, April 26, 2006
    - Pittsburgh City Controller Candidates and Pittsburgh City Council Candidates, April 11, 2007
    - Mayoral Candidates and Pittsburgh City Council Candidates, April 23, 2009
    - Gubernatorial Candidates and Lieutenant Governor Candidates, April 28, 2010
    - Allegheny County Chief Executive Candidates and Allegheny County Controller Candidates, May 9, 2011
    - PA State Representative Candidates, April 11, 2012
    - Mayoral Candidates, May 2, 2013
    - Pittsburgh City Council Candidates, April 30, 2015
    - PA State Representatives Candidates, April 7, 2016
    - Mayoral, City Council, County Council Candidates, May 3, 2017
  - Members Orientations, 5.
    Twice a year, the Chamber offers a Members Orientation program to emphasize the value of being part of an organized body and the benefits associated with the membership. The 'Boxed Luncheon' programs are open to new and existing members.
    - New Members' Orientation Flyer, June 24, 2008
    - New Members' Orientation Flyer, January 23, 2009
    - New Members' Orientation Flyer, June 23, 2009
    - New Members' Orientation Flyer, February 5, 2010
    - Members' Orientation Flyer, July 8, 2010
    - Members' Orientation Flyer, February 4, 2011
    - Members' Orientation Flyer, January 25, 2012
    - Members' Orientation Flyer, June 26, 2012
    - Members' Orientation Flyer, February 19, 2013
    - Members' Orientation Flyer, June 19, 2013
    - Members' Orientation Flyer, January 28, 2014
    - Members' Orientation Flyer, June 30, 2014
    - Members' Orientation Flyer, Januray 28, 2015
    - Members' Orientation Flyer, July 28, 2015
    - Members' Orientation-Flyer, January 29, 2016
    - Members' Orientation-Flyer, June 23, 2016
    - Members' Orientation-Flyer, January 26, 2017
    - Members' Orientation Flyer, June 29, 2017
    - Members Orientation, January 25, 2018
    - Members Orientation, June 21, 2018
  - Members Mixers, 6.
    An offering to the membership that began as a quarterly event, 'Mixers' are a way for Chamber Members to develop relationships with one another, exchange business cards, and share information that may be of mutual benefit. In 2004, the program began a monthly event with corporations and non-profits agreeing to serve as the sponsor and host the event.
    - Manchester Craftsman Guild, January 25, 1998
    - National Aviary, April 16, 1999
    - Manchester Craftsman's Guild, September 9, 1999
    - Dowe's, April 20, 2000
    - National City Bank, September 28, 2000
    - One PNC Plaza, January 25, 2001
    - Dowe's, April 26, 2001
    - New PNC Park, June 29, 2001
    - Andy Warhol Museum, September 2001
    - National City Center, January 31, 2002
    - Renaissance Pittsburgh Hotel, April 30, 2002
    - Advanced Technology Systems Inc, June 27, 2002
    - John Heinz History Center, September 30, 2002
    - National City Center, May 6, 2003
    - Grace Robinson Insurance Agency Inc, June 26, 2003
    - Crawford Grill on the Square, November 24, 2003
    - Manchester Bidwell Corporation, March 29, 2004
    - Highmark Caring Place, April 29, 2004
    - One PNC Plaza, June 22, 2004
    - Crawford Grill on the Square, July 27, 2004
    - PNC Park, August 13, 2004
    - ALCOA Corporate Center, September 29, 2004
    - YMCA of Greater Pittsburgh, October 26, 2004
    - Fifth Avenue Place, January 26, 2005
    - Frick Art and Historical Center, March 22, 2005
    - Ambiance Boutique, March 25, 2005
    - One Mellon Center, April 25, 2005
    - Society for Contemporary Craft, June 30, 2005
    - New Crawford Grill on the Square, September 29, 2005
    - Kingsley Association Pittsburgh, October 26, 2005
    - National City Bank of Pennsylvania, January 25, 2006
    - Carnegie Museum of Art, March 31, 2006
    - YMCA of Greater Pittsburgh, April 26, 2006
    - Phipps Conservatory & Botanical Gardens, June 27, 2006
    - Frick Art and Historical Center, September 19, 2006
    - Fifth Avenue Place, October 26, 2006
    - One PNC Plaza, January 25, 2007
    - One PNC Plaza, March 27, 2007
    - #1 Cochran of Monroeville, April 26, 2007
    - Northside Urban Pathways, May 23, 2007
    - Phipps Conservatory and Botanical Gardens, June 28, 2007
    - Citizens Bank of Pennsylvania, September 27, 2007
    - Fifth Avenue Place, October 25, 2007
    - Society for Contemporary Craft, January 24, 2008
    - Regional Enterprise Tower - Lobby, March 27, 2008
    - One PNC Plaza, April 29, 2008
    - NEED Warner Center, May 22, 2008
    - Mount Washington, June 18, 2008
    - Urban Settlement Services LLC, September 30, 2008
    - Fifth Avenue Place, October 23, 2008
    - Heinz Hall, February 27, 2009
    - Bank of New York Mellon, April 30, 2009
    - Mattress Factory, May 21, 2009
    - EQT Plaza, September 30, 2009
    - Fifth Avenue Place, October 22, 2009
    - Rivers Casino, January 8, 2010
    - Three Rivers Youth, March 30, 2010
    - Engine House Twenty Five, May 25, 2010
    - Manchester Bidwell Corporation, June 22, 2010
    - Renaissance Pittsburgh Hotel, August 26, 2010
    - Special Mixer Renaissance Pittsburgh Hotel, August 26, 2010
    - Legislative Reception, October 7, 2010
    - Fifth Avenue Place, October 28, 2010
    - Renewable Manufacturing Gateway, January 27, 2011
    - Citizens Bank of PA, March 28, 2011
    - Savoy Restaurant, April 19, 2011
    - Larrimor's, May 26, 2011
    - Mixer Map, June 2011
    - Carnegie Mellon University, June 22, 2011
    - Senator John Heinz History Center, September 21, 2011
    - Pittsburgh Zoo and PPG Aquarium, October 28, 2011
    - Executive Cigars, LLC, January 31, 2012
    - Carnegie Museum of Art, March 29, 2012
    - EQT Building, April 24, 2012
    - P.J. Dick, Trumbull Corporation, Lindy Paving, April 26, 2012
    - DoubleTree by Hilton Hotel & Suites Pittsburgh Downtown, May 24, 2012
    - The Children's Home of Pittsburgh & Lemieux Family Center, June 22, 2012
    - Rivers Casino, September 27, 2012
    - Fifth Avenue Place, October 23, 2012
    - Senator John Heinz History Center, January 29, 2013
    - Larrimor's, February 28, 2013
    - Dollar Bank, March 27, 2013
    - Allegheny HYP Club, April 24, 2013
    - PNC Park, June 18, 2013
    - Consol Energy Center, September 24, 2013
    - Huntington Bank, October 22, 2013
    - Frick Art and Historical Center, January 29, 2014
    - Pittsburgh Community Services Inc, February 18, 2014
    - Koppers Building, March 26, 2014
    - Pittsburgh Athletic Association, April 30, 2014
    - Up Modern Kitchen, May 22, 2014
    - CCAC, June 5, 2014
    - Environment and Energy Community Outreach Center, September 30, 2014
    - Carnegie Museum of Natural History, October 16, 2014
    - Fifth Avenue Place, January 21, 2015
    - Caffe Amante, January 21, 2015
    - East End Cooperative Ministry, February 23, 2015
    - Le Maison Du Paix, March 31, 2015
    - Center for Organ Recovery and Education, April 29, 2015
    - Hosanna House, May 28, 2015
    - Skyline Terrace, June 25, 2015
    - Childrens Museum of Pittsburgh, September 29, 2015
    - Laurel Highlands Council Boy Scouts of America, October 28, 2015
    - Savoy Restaurant, November 30, 2015
    - DoubleTree by Hilton Suites Pittsburgh, January 28, 2016
    - VisitPittsburgh, February 16, 2016
    - Energy Innovation Center, March 22, 2016
    - Center for Organ Recovery and Education, April 27, 2016
    - EQT Corporation, May 25, 2016
    - Frick Art and Historical Center, June 22, 2016
    - DoubleTree by Hilton Hotel & Suites, September 21, 2016
    - University of Pittsburgh, October 25, 2016
    - Citizens Bank, January 19, 2017
    - Greater Pittsburgh Chamber of Commerce, February 9, 2017
    - Carnegie Science Center, March 29, 2017
    - Pittsburgh Public Schools, April 27, 2017
    - Joint Mixer Meeting at Highmark Stadium, May 25, 2017
    - Manchester Bidwell Corporation, June 22, 2017
    - Don Kartlandt Home, September 13, 2017
    - Amachi Pittsburgh, October 26, 2017
    - Dollar Bank, November 30, 2017
    - Carnegie Museum of Art, December 14, 2017
    - Pittsburgh Symphony Orchestra, January 18, 2018
    - Pittsburgh Pirates, February 21, 2018
    - Koppers Building, March 27, 2018
    - Roman Bistro, April 17, 2018
    - Citizens Bank, May 31, 2018
    - Big Brothers Big Sisters of Greater Pittsburgh, June 28, 2018
  - PowerBreakfast Meetings, 7.
    The third Friday morning of each month between September and June are designated as the time for Chamber Members to officially meet. A decision maker from government or private industry is invited to present their major business objectives and how Chamber Members can engage in procurement opportunities. Upcoming events and business items are presented along with the introduction of new members since the last PowerBreakfast Meeting.
    - Mark Roosevelt Superintendent Pittsburgh Public Schools, January 19, 2007
    - Hon. Dennis Yablonsky Secretary of Community and Economic Development - Commonwealth of PA, February 16, 2007
    - County Chief Executive Dan Onorato County of Allegheny, March 16, 2007
    - Morgan O'Brien President & CEO Duquesne Light, April 24, 2007
    - Christine Griffin Commissioner U.S. Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, June 15, 2007
    - Robert Nelkin New President & CPO United Way of Allegheny County, July 20, 2007
    - Mr. Robert A. DeMichiei Chief Financial Officer University of Pittsburgh Medical Center, September 21, 2007
    - Sr. Stuart G. Hoffman Senior VP & Chief Economist PNC Financial Services Group Inc, October 19, 2007
    - County Chief Executive Dan Onorato County of Allegheny, January 18, 2008
    - Neil A. Barclay J.D. President & CEO August Wilson Center for African American Culture, February 15, 2008
    - Gregory S. Babe President & CEO Bayer Material Science LLC, March 14, 2008
    - Arthur P. Ziegler Jr. President Pittsburgh History and Landmarks Foundation - Howard B. Slaughter Jr. CEO Landmarks Community Capital Corp of Pittsburgh, April 18, 2008
    - Stephen Bland President and CEO Port Authority of Allegheny County, June 19, 2008
    - Keith B. Key President and CEO KBK Enterprises LLC, July 18, 2008
    - Dr. Alex Johnson President Community College of Allegheny County, September 19, 2008
    - Mayor Luke Ravenstahl City of Pittsburgh, October 17, 2008
    - County Chief Executive Dan Onorato County of Allegheny, January 16, 2009
    - John Craig President Pittsburgh Regional Indicators, February 20, 2009
    - Ellen Kight President Pittsburgh Partnership for Neighborhood Development, March 20, 2009
    - State Representative Joseph Preston Jr. District 24 and State Representative Jake Wheatley Jr. District 19, April 17, 2009
    - Elizabath Schroeder Executive Director Riverlife, June 19, 2009
    - Dennis Yablonsky CEO Allegheny Conference on Community Development, July 10, 2009
    - Senator Wayne D. Fontana Pennsylvania Senate, September 18, 2009
    - Commissioner J. Bracken Burns Sr. Washington County, PA, October 16, 2009
    - Mark Peterson President Bridgeway Capital, January 15, 2010
    - Petra Mitchell President and CEO Catalyst Connection, February 19, 2010
    - Kent D. McElhattan, Chairman & Co-Founder Industrial Scientific Corporation, March 26, 2010
    - Rob Stephany, Executive Director Urban Redevelopment Authority of Pittsburgh, April 16, 2010
    - Allen G. Kukovich Executive Director Power of 32 - Regional Visioning Project, June 18, 2010
    - James Golding Managing Director - Purchasing FEDEX Ground, September 17, 2010
    - Sunil Wadhwani, Co-Chairman iGate Corporation, October 22, 2010
    - Randall Dearth President and CEO LANXESS, January 21, 2011
    - Kathryn Z. Klaber President and Executive Director Marcellus Shale Coalition, February 18, 2011
    - EQT, April 15, 2011
    - Dr.Linda Lane, Superintendent Pittsburgh Public Schools, April 25, 2011
    - Stephen Bland, CEO Port Authority of Allegheny County, June 17, 2011
    - Senator Wayne D. Fontana PA Senate, July 15, 2011
    - Robert Morris University, September 16, 2011
    - Chief Maurita Bryant, Pittsburgh Chapter President National Organization of black Law Enforcement Executives (NOBLE), October 21, 2011
    - Randy Woelfel CEO NOVA Chemicals, January 20, 2012
    - Michael Lamb Controller City of Pittsburgh, February 17, 2012
    - Hon. Richard Fitzerald Chief Executive County of Allegheny, March 16, 2012
    - Duke Rupert President and CEO West Penn Hospital, April 20, 2012
    - Hon Jack Wagner Auditor General Commonwealth of PA, July 13, 2012
    - Stephen Bland CEO Port Authority of Allegheny County, June 15, 2012
    - The Hon. Robert P. Casey United States Senator Commonwealth of PA, August 24, 2012
    - Eric C. Shiner The Andy Warhol Museum, September 21, 2012
    - LaVaughn Henry Ph.D. VP & Senior Regional Officer Federal Reserve Bank of Cleveland, October 19, 2012
    - Arletta Scott Williams ALCOSAN, January 18, 2013
    - Neal Binstock, Senior Director, Business Operations Robert Morris University, February 15, 2013
    - Robert Rubinstein Acting Executive Director Urban Redevelopment Authority of Pittsburgh, March 15, 2013
    - Hon Richard Fitzgerald, Chief Executive County of Allegheny, April 15, 2013
    - Scott Miller and Darrell Smalley Ernst and Young, June 14, 2013
    - Daniel K. Fitzpatrick President and CEO Citizens Bank of PA, July 19, 2013
    - Mike Schiller LEED Green Associate Green Building Alliance, September 27, 2013
    - Mekael Teshome Asst VP and Economist PNC, October 18, 2013
    - Honorable Rich Fitzgerald Chief Executive for the County of Allegheny, January 17, 2014
    - Paul Harper Clinical Assistant Professor at the University of Pittsburgh Katz Graduate School of Business, February 21, 2014
    - Mayor William Peduto of the City of Pittsburgh, March 21, 2014
    - Dewitt Peart President of the Greater Pittsburgh Chamber of Commerce, April 25, 2014
    - Guhan Venkatu VP and Senior Regional Officer, June 20, 2014
    - Mike Doyle Congressman of the United States House of Representatives, July 7, 2014
    - Robert A. DeMichiei Executive VP and CFO for UPMC, September 19, 2014
    - Dr. Quintin Bullock President of Community College of Allegheny County, October 17, 2014
    - Honorable Rich Fitzgerald Chief Executive for the County of Allegheny, January 16, 2015
    - Ellen M. McLean CEO of Port Authority of Allegheny County, February 20, 2015
    - Mayor William Peduto of the City of Pittsburgh, March 30, 2015
    - Keith B. Key President and CEO of KBK Enterprises, April 17, 2015
    - Jo Ellen Parker President and CEO of Carnegie Museums of Pittsburgh, June 19, 2015
    - Cameron McLay Police Chief for the City of Pittsburgh, July 10, 2015
    - Frank Coonelly President of the Pittsburgh Pirates, September 18, 2015
    - Jeremy Waldrup President and CEO of Pittsburgh Downtown Partnership, October 16, 2015
    - Christina Cassotis CEO of Allegheny County Airport Authority, November 20, 2015
    - Honorable Richard Fitzgerald Chief Executive for Allegheny County, January 15, 2016
    - Honorable Dennis Davin Secretary for the PA Department of Community and Economic Development, February 19, 2016
    - Mayor Bill Peduto of the City of Pittsburgh, March 18, 2016
    - Dana Yealy Managing Director for Federal Home Loan Bank of Pittsburgh, April 15, 2016
    - Richard Hudic Executive Director for Allegheny Regional Asset District, June 17, 2016
    - Matt Smith President and the Greater Pittsburgh Chamber of Commerce, July 22, 2016
    - Robin Nicholson Director of The Frick Pittsburgh, September 16, 2016
    - Christopher Hahn General Director for the Pittsburgh Opera, October 14, 2016
    - Honorable Rich Fitzgerald County Executive of Allegheny County, January 20, 2017
    - Dr. Anthony Hamlet Superintendent for Pittsburgh Public Schools, February 17, 2017
    - Mayor Bill Peduto of the City of Pittsburgh, March 17, 2017
    - Jerry MacCleary President of Covestro, April 21, 2017
    - James McQuade President of Dollar Bank, June 23, 2017
    - Arletta Scott Williams Executive Director of ALCOSAN, September 15, 2017
    - Richard Jewell Commissioner of the Pa Gaming Control Board, October 20, 2017
    - County Executive Rich Fitzgerald, 2020-01-17
    - Pennsylvania State Representatives, 2020-02-14
    - Mark Anthony Thomas, 2020-09-18
  - Junior Chamber of Commerce, 8.
    Scope and Contents
    We have a partnership with Community College of Allegheny County in which we developed new programs....
    - The Connection Between Credit and Your Business Workshop, April 5, 2018
    - Basic Bookkeeping Principles For Your Business Workshop, April 18, 2018
    - Understanding Legal Issues for Your Business Workshop, May 3, 2018
  - Golf Clinic, 9.
    - Golf Clinic Flyer, May 25, 2018
    - Golf Clinic Registration Form
    - Golf Clinic Regular Sponsorship levels
    - Golf Clinic Art of the Scramble, May 31, 2019
- Financials, III.
  The Chamber is managed by a certified public accounting firm and produces an annual report each year on the continued strength and viability of the organization. All reports and financial information is contained here within.
- Multimedia, IV.
  This category features the different forms of media on the events and programs produced by the Chamber. This includes audio, video, still images, all either printed or hand produced.